Companies like Uber, Rapolit, LinkedIn uses a framework called Langraph to build agents that are not just powerful
but reliable. There are so many agent AI frameworks out there and Langraph is one of the popular framework. In this
particular crash course, we will look at some theoretical fundamentals first and then we will dive deeper into langraph
covering a range of topics which I have displayed on the screen right now. I also want to take a moment to thank Jad
Brains for sponsoring this video. As part of this collaboration, you all will get 3 month free subscription of PyCharm
Pro. More details on that later. Let's start with agentic AI fundamentals through Langraph. We will be building AI
agents. So, it's important you know what it is. And if you already know this concept, feel free to skip to the next
section. When you have a simple LLM and when you ask a question, it can give limited answer. based on its training
cutoff. So let's say if you ask questions specific to your organization, it won't be answered because it doesn't
have access to this data. In my own company Atlake Technologies, we have 55 people and we want to build this HR
assistant chatboard where you can ask policy related questions such as how many vacation days are there or what is
the policy on seclive and so on and you can build such a system using a rag architecture. So let's say you have all
this policy data in a PDF file. You can point LLM to that knowledge using retrieval augmented generation then you
can ask any question and generate the answers. If you don't know about rag you will find many videos on YouTube but rag
is one architecture that gets used to assist LLM with external knowledge. Do we call this agent? No. Anthropic
defines AI systems which are built using LLM as in two categories. Okay. So the first
one is workflows. Second one is an agent. So workflows are systems where LLM and tools are orchestrated through
predefined code paths. So whatever we just saw was workflow. Let's say you enhance this chatboard further where it
can ask specific question for a person. Let's say moan is logged in and he's asking how many leaves do I have left.
It will specifically look for moan's data. Okay, 7 days left and so on. Is this call agent? Once again, no. So here
what's happening is LLM is having access to all the policy documents. So moan can ask general policy documents as well.
But LLM is also pointing to the HR database. So that through some API let's say and when you say okay as moan how
many leaves are left for me it will just retrieve that particular answer. This is called tool augmented chatboard. Now
let's complicate this further and imagine a chatbot that can prepare for Sara's maternity leave or it can onboard
a new employee. Now when you're onboarding a new employee, you have to perform various steps. You have to
schedule a welcome meeting where you will need access to outlook. You will create interns profile in HR management
system for which you need access to HRMS through some API let's say. Then you will create uh tickets to order laptop
etc. So here you are doing goal oriented planning. So you have a goal here bigger goal. It's a complex task and you are
kind of planning this. You are doing multi-step reasoning you know and multi-step planning and doing autonomous
decision making. Okay. Now as a system you have LLM as a core component but you have access to all these tools. Okay.
Outlook, HRMS, Slack these are all the tools that you have. Okay. You also have knowledge which is the database or any
documents you have. All right. So uh this is called an agent. Okay, it's an agentic chatboard because it can do
multi-step planning, multi-step reasoning just like how we as a humans will do it. And it has some level of
autonomy. Okay, some level of control. Of course, you can't give it an access to your bank's password etc. Otherwise,
it will do crazy things. But you give some control that hey LLM I'm giving you this control and within that control you
can take autonomous decisions. So AI agent is something that can make decisions and take actions on its own to
an extent. Okay. So you have to remember there is some some form of control here. You can't give agent access to you know
your Bitcoin wallet and things like that. There is some level of control but within that control it can take
autonomous decision. It can take actions on its own to achieve a goal without being told explicitly what to do. And
agentic AI you will hear these two terms AI agent and agentic AI. Agent AI is nothing but a system that is using one
or more agents. Okay they are similar things. So this is the chart that is showing the comparison between the three
in the first rack chatboard where you were asking policy questions. It is reactive but it's it doesn't use tool
reasoning planning proactivity. Okay. Whereas agent AI is using uh tool use reasoning planning proactivity and so
on. One of the biggest problems with agents is reliability. They are like monkeys. You are giving them some tools
and they can do all kind of crazy things. So you need to control them. If you plot a chart of agent's level of
control to its reliability, as you can see here, as you increase the control, the reliability will drop. So if you
have a fully autonomous agent just like that monkey, the reliability will go down. Okay, this is the general issue
with any agents. Lang graph is a framework that will help you increase the reliability for agents. Okay.
Langraph comes with lot of tools and features which will help you bend this graph and you can increase the
reliability of these autonomous agent. Okay. So it's a framework that helps you build reliable agents. Now how it
differs from other frameworks such as Agno, Google ADK and so on. Agno is very lightweight and fast. Google ADK on the
other hand has tight GCP integration. It allows you to build multi- aent system using Google's A2A protocol and so on.
Whereas Lang graph provides a more expressive customizable framework to build highly complex agents. Okay. So
it's very customizable. In other frameworks when I use them personally what I see is it's sort of like a black
box. Okay. you can't customize things beyond certain points. Whereas in Langraphph, you can go underneath at a
deeper level and customize things and create complex agents. Also, it excels at graph-based stateful orchestration.
We'll go over graph and state and so on. I know these things might sound like jargon but just in case if you know
about graph data structure and a stateful orchestration the langraph will allow you to do that okay it will allow
you to do multi-step workflows with memory streaming human in the loop control some of you might be familiar
with langchain framework and a natural question is what is the difference between these two frameworks well
sometimes you want to build AI system where let's say you are getting uh data from some database okay in step one then
you are doing some data cleaning then you are giving it to LLM for extracting some information or summarizing or doing
some work okay then you are performing some other step then again you're calling LLM you can have this kind of a
workflow system remember workflow from that anthropic document so this is that same workflow it's a linear workflow
which is called a chain and whenever you want to build this kind of workflows, lang chain framework is ideal and in
fact we have a couple of videos and one complete YouTube project where we built uh this kind of chain using lang chain.
Okay, where we uh retrieved the documents for which we use text loader class from lang chain. Okay, so these
are all the classes and tools provided by langchain frameworks. Langchain frameworks provides so many amazing
utilities which can be used in langraph too. by the way. Okay. So this is one example of a chain that we created in
one of our rocky boat project in in YouTube. Okay. So here you will use lang chain. Now when do you use langraph?
Well when you have some kind of autonomy that is given to LLM. For example, here you start at some point and LLM will
decide okay whether it wants to call step A, step B or whether it wants to make call to LLM, you know, another LLM
and then this LLM will also have some kind of autonomy. It will internally decide if if it wants to call step C,
step D, E, it can also call by the way previous LLM. You see this pathway. So here this kind of decision control is
given to this LLM. It is done by this LLM in autonomous way. Okay, autonomy is a keyword folks. So LLM is like a human
brain, right? It it it is smart. It can make that decision. You just give instruction that okay, you are given
this task and just figure out from this step CD E these three steps and it will determine it on its own. You're not
going to write some code etc. Okay, I mean you'll write code for giving a prompt but the decision is made by LLM.
Okay, so here you have a human brain. Here you have a human like like sort of like a human brain and it's making all
these independent decisions and you are seeing this graph type of data structure. Okay. So you have a graph
where you can have like this kind of you know like like cycles and so on and it is represented as stateful workflows
which is a graph. Okay. So for this scenario you will use lang graph. So let's outline the differences in a table
format. You use lang chain to build llm apps. Okay chains tools and agents. Whereas langraph is used to manage
complex workflows with state. Okay. So it will have a state and that state will pass through different nodes in the
graph. In lang chain you have linear and reactive chains. Whereas in lang graph you have graph based support loops,
retries and memories. Okay. So there is some kind of autonomy. When you're retrying let's say you are doing
something it doesn't work it will retry again. It's like debugging your code. You write code you get an error you see
the error you update it. You again run it. you know it's like a retry like you're fixing and there's a feedback
loop. So you'll see all of that in this lang graph and the best use case for lang chain is simple chatboards rack
tool usage whereas for complex workflows you know in our HR assistant chatboard when we said onboard new employee for
this that kind of workflow which is multi-step agent with memory you will use langraph okay uh here the state
handling is partially stateful or stateless in lang chain whereas in lang graph
it is fully stateful. So there is a state that you will pass. Okay. So let's say in in
lang graph you will have this kind of graph right. So you begin you have this kind of graph. This can have nodes.
Okay. It can be any graph and you will be passing a state. So there will be a state. So there is some kind of state
that you pass. So you pass it here. same state is being passed here. We will uh have a separate section on this so you
will understand and each of these nodes will modify this state. Okay. And then
example use case for lang is book a flight simple API whereas langraph you use it for complex thing like plan a
vacation multiple step multi-step reasoning planning and so on. They also have something called lang by the way.
So lang we'll we'll produce a separate video in the future on lang. So this lang is used for observability debugging
testing and monitoring. Okay. Whereas lang graph and lang chain these are opensource systems. Okay. There are two
frameworks in the lang chain ecosystem. They also have this lang platform which is used for deployment. Before we start
writing code, let's install some necessary stuff. The first one is IDE. We are going to use PyCharm. I love this
editor. Jet Brains is an official sponsor of this video and they have this unified editor. So previously they used
to have community version and pro version. Now there is a single version. Okay. So when you download, so just
click on download and it will just download the latest version. Okay. So I clicked on it and then I will install
it. So if you go back on their page you will see that uh by default whatever version you get is pro actually. So you
get 1 month of pro included and after that it is free forever with community features but as part of our
collaboration with PyCharm you're going to get extended free subscription of pro. Okay. So,
check the video description below for the coupon code. Uh we want to thank uh Jet Brains for this partnership. After
you uh downloaded it, obviously you will go through common sense steps. Double click, install, remove any previous
versions that you have. And I have this latest version of PyCharm ready. I will also create a directory to store all my
code. So C code is a directory where I keep all my code. So here I'm going to create
maybe lang graph learning you know lang graph learning that kind of folder I'll store all my code here
and here you will just say open C code just open that folder you know lang graph learning
okay select the folder so it will open that up here. All right. Now,
you will also explore this AI assistant that is inbuilt in PyCharm. So, you get this AI pro for free for 30 days. Just
click on let's go to enable it. Okay. All right. So, see this is enabled. Now, you can pick your model from here. You
can ask it to write code, whatever. We are going to use AI assistant and some of the cool features of PyCharm
throughout the entire tutorial. We will also install UV which is an efficient Python package manager. You can use it
as a replacement of pip. Click on installation step here and I have Windows. So I'm going to copy this
command and put it in my Windows command prompt. Okay. So I'm using Windows command prompt. Here I will put it add
and it will add UV. We'll use UV to install other necessary Python packages. Okay. Now we have created this langraph
learning uh folder. So let's go into that folder and then you will have access to this UV
command. You will just say UV in it and it will perform some necessary initialization. So if you check here, it
added pi project.toml file. I will go over what it is. Uh it's just necessarily your package management.
Then it also added Python version. So I have Python 3.10 by the way. Uh it's okay even if you have 3.11 or a later
version. I'm going to use 3.10. Then you have git ignore. So you can enhance this. you know you can add
whatever extra files here. So this is the project structure that it has created and PyCharm is asking me to
select a valid Python interpreter. So what I'm going to do is I will create virtual environment using UV and the way
you do that is you will install necessary Python uh packages. So for now what I need is langraph. So you can just
say uv add in that directory lang graph I also need python dot environment I need notebook. So just add and you'll
see it's so fast it created virtual environment here. See v environment and it also
added all the dependencies. So you will see this toml file being updated. See all the dependencies are added and the
exit dependencies are expanded in this uv.log file. Okay. So these are internal details. You don't need to worry. You
can treat it as a black box. Whatever you want to install. Uh previously with pip you will say pip install something.
Now with uv you are saying uv add that particular thing. Now let me configure python interpreter. So click on
configure python interpreter. uh go to interpreter settings and here just say add interpreter add
local interpreter. Okay, select existing and click on this folder icon. Okay, folder icon and here you need to select
the virtual environment. So we have langraph learning okay which has venv folder that's your virtual environment.
Go to scripts and in scripts you need to pick up a python.exe. Okay. Make sure you're selecting the
Python interpreter within the virtual environment which is created by UV. So once you hit okay
all right now your environment is all set. Graph is a most fundamental data structure in langraph. So let's
understand some of the basics. If you have taken computer science classes, you will know graph uh already. So graph is
nothing but nodes and ages. So let's say you have Google map, right? Like and you have all these cities. Let's say you
have Delhi, New York, Mumbai, etc. So these cities are sort of like nodes. Okay? So whatever round you are seeing,
they are nodes. And the thing that connects these two nodes are called ages.
Okay. So going back to our example of Google map. Let's say this is Delhi. Okay. And from Delhi I'm going to
Mumbai. Just think about this as a road between Delhi and Mumbai. You know some expressway.
Graphs can also have cycles you know and graphs are used to represent things like your Facebook connections. So in in your
Facebook uh when you have friends so you your friend they are all nodes and your relationship let's say you're a friend
family whatever you know same way with LinkedIn those things are ages so we will build our first simple graph in a
lang graph and for that we are going to use an example of uh let's say your stock trading account let's say you have
stock trading account in Robin Hood or zeroda you put money in let's say you are investing in corporate bonds and you
get almost similar kind of fixed uh return let's say around 8%. Okay. Now I live in US. I invest money and sometimes
you know I'm from India. So I have this mindset of looking at my portfolio in INR Indian rupees. So what I do is I
invest money and then I get the return and then I calculate the total amount and then I convert it to INR. Okay. So
if you think about that uh in terms of a graph what you have is you have your input amount. Okay. Let's say you have
input amount in zerod. Let's say you put or let's say bank account you put some $1,000 and you have your first node
which will calculate your total amount including interest. So let's say you are getting interest or let's say bond is
giving you 8% return. Okay. So here this is your first node and after you get 8% return your total okay your total in USD
is going to be 1,000 into 8%. So 8% is like so if you do this you will get the total amount okay and then in node two I
would like to convert this amount into INR. Okay. So this one the first node let's say if you have to write python
function we can say calc total this will be my function and the second function will be convert
to INR and when you do that like your total INR will be whatever is your total USD
amount multiplied by the exchange rate let's say right now it's 85 so this okay and that's the amount you get uh as an
output. Okay. Now the way lang graph uh graphs work is they will consume something called a state. So if you have
taken some computer science classes uh you will know about this state. So state is let's say an object. Okay. So state
is an object which gets passed between the nodes and this state will have all these parameters right. So it will have
amount it will have total USD total USD it will have total INR and so on and
you pass this state you know like like it goes through this node and you get new state again you get new state so
you're not calling these nodes by function etc it's just a state whatever you want to pass single object you pass
it and it just comes out so let me write the code folks this is very very simple. Uh you you will be amazed how simple
this thing is. So let's create a notebook. Now uh this PyCharm version allows you to write notebooks
uh inside the ID. Okay? So you don't have to go outside. And I will just call it simple graph.
Now what I love about uh this is it will give you AI autocomplete. Okay. So first thing that we are going to do is we will
define our state. Okay. So this state this red square is an object a python dictionary or let's say class. Okay. So
let's define that. So I will say class portfolio state.
Okay. And now I want this to be derived from type
dict. So in Python you you know about this uh thing typing right? So this way you create type
hints. You know Python is not a statically typed language but you can use this typing hints to define data
types of your members. So here once you derive this from type dict you'll be able to define the types. Okay. So here
I will have amount USD which will be float. Now see this is what I like about AI editor like
when you're typing something it will try to autocomplete and then you will have total
USD which is float. See I'm just hitting tab and then you have total INR and that is also float. So control enter
or just hit this button. See it is running this. And then the next one will be I will just create an object just to
kind of show you right. So my object um and how do you define the types in Python? Well once again Python is a
dynamically typed language. So when you say colon this you are defining a type hint not the exact type. And here you
can have amount USD whatever
and then you have total USD and then you have total INR. Okay. Now when you do this it works okay but let's
say if I have improper key see you will see this kind of type hint. See this bulb. So it is saying that there are
incorrect types. Okay. Okay, so that's the whole idea of doing this type dict. All right, my state object which is this
red object is defined. Now I need to define these two nodes which is nothing but a simple Python function that state
as an input. Okay, so you will have calc total. It will take portfolio state as an input and it will output the
portfolio state. Okay. So, portfolio state will be my output. And here what you are getting is uh
let's say I want to call this object state. In the state the total USD amount that I
have is nothing but the amount in USD multiply by the return rates. Let's say I'm getting 8% fixed return. Okay.
And I will just return this state back. Okay. So you're getting state as an input. You are returning state as an
output as per this diagram. This red square will pass between the nodes. So say same thing for the second function
which is convert to INR. So I'll just copy paste folks just to save time on recording. Pretty straightforward. you
are getting state as an input, state as an output and this is how you define the data type of output using the Python
type hints. Okay? And in this function what you're doing is you're saying total INR is nothing but whatever is the total
amount in USD multiplied by 85. Now in real life situation you will get the live conversion rates using some APIs.
Here it's a learning tutorial so we don't need to bother about all of that. All right. So let's execute this. This
is done. Now I will go ahead and define my graph. So lang graph dot graph import state graph. Okay. And my
builder. So there is something called builder which will let you define that graph. Okay. So here the state is your
portfolio state. So that is what you're passing it as an input. Okay. And in the graph what do you do? Well, you add
nodes. Okay, first you add nodes and then you define the relationship which is like ages. So I will just add a node
here saying add node and calculate total. Now you can also define the name of the node. Okay. So my
you can also call it calculate total node, right? calc total and then same way you will say
uh this one is convert to INR and this is convert to INR node. Okay. So these are the two nodes you have added. Now
you need to add ages to define the relationship. Okay. So it will always start with uh something called a start
age. Okay. So here you you will begin with this start age. So you are starting with a start age and then you will end
with the end age. So let's start with that builder dot add age
and in add age you will have start. So start is a constant that you can import from this.
So from start first I want to calculate the total correct and then from total I want to go to INR and from INR I want
to go to N. Now you just notice like my AI autocomplete is completing it. So I'm saving a lot of time when I use this AI
assistant. I feel like I have got some iron man kind of superpower. You know my productivity goes up because I don't
have to type so many things. You can also use this AI assistant code here and you can just say whatever you want to
do, right? Like you can just say okay complete the code for builder
and display the graph using I display. So when you do that it is generating the code. See
you see. So that way it is useful. So I'll just delete it um just to kind of show you manually before I show you how
to display the graph. We need to build it. So we'll just say graph is equal to builder dot compile.
And this is the code. You just copy paste. You don't need to remember syntax etc. to display the
graph. So as you can see here it has a start node. Then there is calc total node convert to INR node and end. Now
you can simply call it by doing this. You can just say graph dot invoke and pass your initial state. Okay. So see on
a $1,000 USD amount uh the total USD is 1080 and total INR is this much. Now when you look at this graph it looks
more like a linear chain. In the next step, we are going to create a graph with some conditions. We will design
this kind of graph where you give your amount as an input and also target currency. So previously we had INR as a
fixed currency. Now I want to supply INR, EUR etc. And based on the target currency, it will call different nodes.
Okay. So let's create a Jupyter notebook here. This will be to graph with condition.
And here I'm going to do some copy paste. Now I don't want this to be total INR.
It is total INR. And you will have a target currency. Okay. So from by the way if you want to support fixed set of
currency you can use literal which will means like just use from these currencies. Okay. So let's say I want
only INR and EUR to be my target currency. Okay. So let's execute this and also copy paste this here.
So I have total USD. I think this function is okay but total INR should be this because we
don't have that total INR variable and let's create a convert to EUR function. Okay, so convert to EUR
will be whatever is the I'm just hard coding 0.9. Whatever is the rate you can put it there. Okay, so let's execute. So
we have this three nodes now. So let's add those three nodes. Okay. So here I will once again copy paste this
calc total node convert to INR node and convert to EUR node. Okay. So this is convert to EUR
EUR. Now let's think about ages. So the first age is this which is okay. You always calculate total and then you add
something called a conditional age. So in conditional age your start key or your source is let's say this one right
kelp total node and then you want to write a function that will help you select you know which
node to go to. So we can say choose conversion is our function. it will get state as an input obviously
portfolio state and I want the string to be the output. It will return a string and and see you can do simply you can
just return the target currency folks. So based on whatever is the target currency you can make a decision. So let
me show you. So once you do that you supply this as a second argument here. Okay. So first argument is the starting
node. Second one is the function. So calculate node calculated a state and state was passed to conversion and what
you got as an output is a string actually. Okay. So here you can do something like
say hello this autocomplete. So the output can be either INR or EUR and you want to map INR to convert to INR node
and convert to UR node. So you're just doing the mapping. Okay. So that's your conditional age. And your last age
is you can do this. You can do either this or you can supply this as an array.
Either way works fine. Okay. So applying this as an array and then graph is equal to builder dot
compile. I run it and then okay I got this error because this function was not defined.
Okay, it ran fine and let's run the graph. See you see like now you see
from calculate node it will use this function which will return which function choose conversion remember
choose conversion will return either UR or INR and based on that it will pick this function
all right now let's run this so you will just say graph dot invoke
and see for INR currency See it is returning this. I mean you can do the math it's correct. Or if you do eur it
is going through a different path of invocation. So congratulation we just created a graph with some conditions and
some kind of routing. Let us now create a simple chatboard state graph. Here we will be using Google Gemini model. You
can use openAI or other model too. You need to create API key first. So just Google Gemini API key and click on this
link and click on get API key or let's say create API key and here it will ask you for the Google project. So you can u
once again Google Google cloud project and here you'll be logging using your Gmail ID obviously and if you click here
you will see all your projects. So just create a new project. Okay, I have already created all these projects. So,
I'm going to select AI agents tutorial. So, AI agents tutorial and create an API key. Once that API key is copied to a
secure place, what you will do is you will create this file called env. Okay? So right click file enviable
Google API key and whatever is your key just copy paste that we will now create a new notebook called
chatbot and we'll load that key into environment variable okay so from dot environment this is the module that we
use when you do this it will set Google Gemini key as an environment variable. Okay. So, execute this and
we'll install some necessary modules now. So, just say UV add lang chain. Lang chain is probably not installed
right now. And the other one is lang chain Google geni. This if you're using openai you have to install a different
module. Okay. Then uh from lang chain dot chat models
okay import init chat model okay and then create an llm
by calling init chat model. So I'll be using Gemini here. And when you do llm invoke and say who was the
first person to walk on moon, it will it will answer that question. Okay. So your basic LLM setup is done and you will see
that it will have this AI message, human message, you know, all those kind of things. All right. So this thing is set
up. Now let's create our uh state graph. Okay, our state graph and our usual setup. So I'm going to remove this
because this is not needed. And here you will create a state and I will also import some necessary models here all in
one go. Okay. So this is type dict and my state like what should be the state? Well, I'm exchanging messages. So
it is good if I have a messages list you know because there is a conversation to maintain the chat history I will have
all the messages being appended into this messages list. So therefore I'm having this and our node will be
chatboard which takes this particular state as input. It will output the same thing
and you will say return you want to return same thing right like messages and you will say that
um so see messages is a list okay and you'll say llm dot invoke whatever llm you created
this okay I I'll run it and you will get more idea on this and then our graph compilation is pretty straightforward
you have start node chat port and compile right so that's pretty straightforward and now I will say graph
dot invoke so this is a common convention that they use where you specify role of user and the actual
message okay so graph dot invoke it expects messages as a state input right you need to add her to this schema
okay and that messages is this message and you will get a response back which
will be again messages. So response messages um you can you can print this and let's
see how this goes. Okay, so I executed this and it says Neil Armstrong. Okay, Neil Armstrong. So it worked as expected
but I don't see the original question. Usually when you are in chat GPD right you see a question from a human right so
there is a human message where we say okay it will ask okay who was the first person to walk on the moon then it will
be an AI human that kind of thing okay so you somehow want to preserve that original question because then if you're
maintaining a chat history it will have a context so in order to do that we need to make some changes here. Okay, here we
are not just saying list but we are saying this is annotated list and then we will say add messages. So add
messages is a built-in function from lang graph what it will do is once you specify this kind of uh syntax it will
automatically preserve the original message. Okay so let me just run it quickly. Okay here annotated is not
defined. Okay, because it is here and I did not execute this cell. Okay, so let me just execute this
and then this. You need to execute all of this. Now when you see it, see human message
is preserved. So first is human message who walked on the moon for the first time and then there is AI message. Okay.
So this uh function by the way is called a reducer function. This particular add message is called a reducer function. It
will add some kind of validation to messages. It will tell it you know that it you don't need to override but you
need to append the new messages which is coming from AI. If you want to understand that in detail you can just
Google langraph reducers. Okay, reducers add message function and you will find some documentation.
Okay, so update state all of that. Um, so I I went to this particular I think where is it? Yeah, here. See, so
this is how reducer works. So when you have this function add messages, right? add messages.
You can read more about it. They have given nice documentation. All right. So, our chatbot is defined. Let's say if you
want to write a loop uh where you can ask question one by one, then you can use this particular code. So, let me
just show it to you. It's just simple while loop, okay? Where you initialize your state to be none. And then in the
first iteration when state is none, see, you're taking the message from the input. Okay? input cell you are taking
the message from and when the state is null you will have simple object like this but next time onwards whatever
messages you have so after first iteration you will have one human message one AI message and then you
append one that the new human message to that okay so that way our chat history is maintained so let me just run it so
here who was the first person to walk on the moon. Print name only. Right? So
when you do that, see it is saying Neil Armstrong. Now you can say, okay, which year? Which year?
And it is saying 1969. See, so there is a context. Now you can ask related questions and it will work. Okay. When I
ask this question, what is the latest price of MSFT stock to the chatbot that we just created? it will say I am unable
to provide real-time stock prices because LLM's knowledge is cut off until certain date and in order to build
useful agents you need to provide tools to agents. So when a person ask questions such as MSFT stock price LLM
should be able to call Yahoo Finance API or some Python function to get the latest uh stock price. So we are going
to now build uh a tool for this chatboard. Okay. So let me just unccommand this
and I have created this four tool call. Okay. So right click jupyer notebook. I created it. I imported couple of
necessary libraries and I will just create the llm in the same way that we did last time.
Okay. So we just created LLM like this. But I want to provide this LLM access of a tool that can get stock prices. Now I
don't want to go to the intricacies of calling Yahoo Finance API etc. What I'll do is I will just define a Python
function and assume it is giving the latest stock price. Okay. So let's say this is the Python function. So I'll
just copy paste. Save some time on typing. And all you're doing is passing the symbol Microsoft, Apple, etc. And it
will just return some dummy value. Okay, in real life industry use case, you will call Yahoo Finance or whatever API. But
for learning, this function is good enough. And you will annotate that as add tool. Okay, so tool is something
that we have imported from lang chain core. And now we have this tool. Then you create this tools variable which
contains all the tools. So let's say if you have second function you know you can have second function third function
you can have a list of tools here and you will now create a variable called llm with tools and you will say llm
dotbind actually there is another method llm.bind bind tools. Okay, let's execute this. So this is looking good and I have
copy pasted same code. Okay, chatboard how you build graph everything remains same. Now here we are going to add one
condition to add the access of tools to this chatboard which is builder dot add conditional age. See you want to call
the tool only if required. If some person is asking question on stock price then it provide access to tool otherwise
you don't need to that's why this is a conditional age which starts with h8 board and it will end in something
called tools condition. Okay. Now tools condition is something that we have imported from lang graph
pre-built and what this will do is it will return either tools or underscore and now what
does that mean? Let me just show you. So here um and by the way I added the tools node as well. Okay so there are like two
changes like this and this. So you added a node for chatboard then you added a node for tools and you have to just say
tool node tools right so tools is this tool node tools and tool node is again a pre-built class that we have called and
the second line that I added is add conditional age from chatboard to tools condition so let me execute this code to
show you so you see here uh what is happening is From chatbot you have a conditional age
going to tools. So why is it dotted? Because only if required then call tools. Otherwise chatboard can directly
go to end. Okay. So chatbot is going to either tools or end. And that is what is specified by tools condition. See it is
going to either tools which is this tools or end. Okay. So that's what this tool condition means. It means from
chatboard when required go to tools otherwise if not required go to end. Okay. And um I think even if you don't
do this should work. Okay. Let me just try this. Yeah. See. All right. So my this thing is done. Now I can just type
in some message. So I'll just say what is the price of Amazon stock right now. and see 150. So it is making a tool call
and it is retrieving 150. What is the price of apple? 100.4. Okay. So 100.4 is something that it should return. And
when you look at the state here, watch this. This is very important. So you had a human message, right? What is the
price of your original question? Then you have a AI message. Okay? And you have this tool call. So see tool
message. So your tool is returning 100.4 and you call get stock price. Okay, you call this get stock price function.
Okay, so here on the AI message you can see the exit function call. uh it is Apple get stock price and this is the
beauty of LLM that from your natural question which is this it intelligently figured out that it needs to call this
and how it did it uses this doc string you know it knows that I have access of this tool which will return the current
price of a stock okay so from this it extracted apple as a stock ticker then it called this function okay uh and if
you look at the state you see that function call see function call argument symbol apple get stock price and the
result is nothing but a simple tool message so 100.4 before was a tool message which you just directly return
to it. But now when I ask a different question, let's say I ask who invented the theory of relativity in that case it
will not call tool. See, you don't see any tool message. So it is smartly figuring out what needs to be done here.
Now let's say I ask this question. I want to buy 20 Amazon stocks then 15 MST. What will be the total cost? Pause
this video and tell me what will happen. Well, you will think that it will first retrieve Amazon 20 stocks then 15 MS FT
and it will tell you the total. See, no, it did not work as per our expectation. So, what it did is it retrieved the MSFT
stock price I think MSF yeah 200.3. So, it made this second tool call, right? And it just retrieved this thing.
It did not do this math actually. So if you look at this state see you see the it made two tool calls actually and 150
and 200 but it is not taking that response back to LLM and LLM should say okay I have this price of MS50 this
price of Amazon let me add up and let me give you the comprehensive final answer. It is not doing that. So this needs some
update. Okay. So for that I will just copy paste. So let let's keep this as it is and Ctrl Ctrl + V and let's call this
tool call agent. Now I want to call it agent because I want to make it more intelligent. Okay. And the only change
you will do here is see right now when you make a tool call it will go directly to the end but you want the response
from tool to go back to chatbot. So for that you will simply say builder dot add age
from tools let's go back to chatbot so now okay I need to execute all of this okay so let's execute all the cells
step by step so look at this chart now from tools also it is going to this chatboard so this is becoming agentic
now Okay. So let me just show you how exactly it is agentic. So this I think let me just directly run
this. See now it is reasoning. Okay. And if you look at the state um
it made those two tool calls right? One for Amazon second for MSFT. And then again it made an AI call. See and it
told you the final result. So it is truly agentic because what happens is you have let's say your chatbot okay so
let's say your chatbot is an LLM based and then you are calling these tools okay so let's say you're calling this
tool to get the stock price and from here you go back and here is the response right so this is a question and
this is a response so first it will uh call it for Amazon. Okay. So, Amazon. Okay. Let's say
whatever is the Amazon price. Okay. Let's say 10. So, 10 goes here. Okay. Then again it
calls it for MSFT. What is the MSFT stock price? Let's say 20. So, 20 goes again here. And it will
do the reasoning. So, it is doing like multi-step planning almost. I mean, I know it's simple but it is doing those
multiple iterations. And therefore if you remember our definition of agent AKI when you give it a tool access it should
be able to call the tool whenever required and it should be able to take back all those response and generate a
comprehensive final output. Let's talk about memory. Now when you are doing a conversation with chatboard you need to
maintain a context. So let's say if you ask a question I want to buy 10 Reliance stocks. What is the price? There will be
price. then you can say I want to buy five MSFT stocks and add the price to the previous total. So it needs to know
what happened previously. Okay, therefore memory is important. And in our code previously we used simple
Python list. So if you look at this one, you see we used Python coding and Python list to append messages to the previous
chat history. And this is not a very efficient way of maintaining memory. Lang graph provides inbuilt constructs
to save the memory. Okay. So we will look into that. So this way works but it's not very efficient. You might run
into the issues. So we will look at the proper way using lang graph inbuilt methods. I'm going to click here crl +
v. Okay. Just copy pasting the last notebook. Let's call it memory. And first let's understand what happens
if you don't have memory. So here if you click on this button it will just run all the cells. And now see let's say if
I ask a different question which is uh get me the current price of
a real stock. Okay. get me the and tell me how many or using a current price. You
can just say using the current price, tell me the total price of 20 10 real stocks
and add it to previous total. Tell me will this work or not? See could you please provide the
previous to it doesn't know what happened previously. So let's use uh this thing called checkpoint memory.
So if you look at the documentation you can import this from lang graph checkpoint memory import memory saver.
Okay. So let me import that here. I think you can import anywhere. So I'm going to import here.
Okay, so you are importing this object of memory saver class and then this memory you will provide while compiling
a graph. So here you will say check pointer is is equal to memory. Okay, so you created
the object while compiling the graph you are saying that take this object of memory. We are not done yet. So one last
step is when you invoke this method. Okay. So let me just remove this. You need to
provide something called config which is a dictionary that will say configurable
and thread ID. Th trade ID let's say my thread ID is one. I'll tell you the value of this thread ID later on. But
for now when you invoke this graph, let's pass this config. Config is equal to config. Okay.
So you got the total price of April stocks. Okay. 100.4. Or let me actually this is not needed.
Let me just remove this cell. Let me add it here. And I will add it to both.
So config here and config here. Same config with same thread ID. So now when I run this, it will tell me
6,04 is the total price. And when I run that, okay, so here is not working because apparently I did not execute the
previous code. So let's execute by clicking on run all and see what happens.
See now it worked. Previously the price was 64. Now 64 + 876 68 80. Isn't this amazing? Now you can maintain two
different threads also. So let me show you. So say if I add a new cell here. Okay. So let me how do I add a new cell?
You can press button B to add a new cell. And let's assume
here I'm creating a different thread ID. Different thread ID. Okay, thread ID too. And here I will say uh let's pick
another stock Apple. Okay. Tell me the current price of five
Apple stocks. Okay. And here the thread ID is two. So when
you run it, see the current price of Apple stock is this. And you're saying like first I'm
having thread ID 1 then I have thread ID 2 thread ID 1 again. So let me just get thread ID. You know what I I think I
need to call it config 1 and two. So config one is this. Config 2 is this. Okay. So here I'm passing config 2. Here
I'm passing config one. Um and then
uh you will say something else. So tell me the current price of five MS stocks and
add it to previous total. Okay.
And just to be on a safe side, I will just execute all the cells. So make sure you are passing config 2 here. Okay,
config 1, config 2, and config 1. So the output of config 1 was $6,04. Correct? And in config 1 again when I
said, okay, add it to previous total. It did not remember Apple's total, but it remember this. See, 6,04 is a previous
total. I hope you're getting it. It's pretty common sense. So it is maintaining two different thread
context. Okay. So if I to uh draw a picture, it will look something like this where I have two threads. Okay. So
I have thread one and then this one is
a thread two. Okay. Okay. So in a thread one in thread two if you look at just thread two we ask for five apple stock
price which is $502 right? So here five apple and the price is $502
and then you add 5 msft. So the five msft is 1, right? So 5 MSFT.
So 5 MSFT is 1,1 and it is just adding these two. So when it adds that you get 15
03, right? So this is my thread two execution. But when I look at
thread one u we asked for we asked this question which where we got 64 and in that 64
you are adding 876 see 876 you are adding to 64. So this um memory is used not only to
maintain context around different threads but it is also useful to resume complex state any time for error
recovery or human in the workflow. Okay. So if you read through it you will realize add memory is not just
maintaining memory for your chat conversation but let's say you are having some kind of error failure and
you want to resume from the last good state. The checkpoint checkpoint is like you are kind of saving you know how do
you save a file in gate or in your IDE and you can say control zt control z so it is just saving checkpoint at certain
point so that you can go back and recover from error when you're done building your agenti application and
when you're ready to deploy to production you want to think about monitoring because agent might be taking
multi-turns and it might be incurring lot of API cost you want to know how many tokens are being used, what is the
cost, what is the latency and you also want to have some kind of trace of output so that you know that your
customers are given the right answers and you can perform some kind of audit. Langsmith is a tool that allows you to
do this and we are going to incorporate it in the code that we have built so far quickly. Okay, so just type
smith.langchain.com and you can login using your Google ID. I'm already logged in. So I see this
kind of setup here where in the home I will see this kind of projects. So I'm going to set up a new project. So just
click on setup tracing and I'll show you it's very easy. Click on generate API key and then add that API key here.
Okay. So I'm going to generate the API key and add it in your env file. Then set this other variable length tracing
true. Langmith endpoint is this and project name is your project name. In our case, it's langraph learning. You
can give any project name by the way. So if you look at all the instructions here, they have given uh those
instructions. Okay. After that, you will u create a new notebook. So let me just create a new notebook uh for I think
let's do it for an agent. Okay. So I'm going to copy paste file tool agent call it 7
um langsmith right lang. And here you will have to install lang
smmith module first. So you will just say uv add lang and it added it easily.
Then you will convert uh this into a function. So, Langsmith allows you to uh upload the traces of your calls via
annotation. Okay. So, you can say from langmmith import traceable and traceable is an annotation
that you can define on top of any function. So, we will define a function called call graph where you just pass in
a question right that you want to ask to your chatboard. and it will answer that question. Okay.
So here call graph will be called on what is the price of let's say apple stock right
now. And this is your query. Okay. And you will return
this particular thing. All right. I will remove the other calls that we have. Actually, you know what? I
think this looks like a better call because it has multiple tool calls involved. So, I will try that. Okay,
just simple one call and click on this to run all the code. Now, when you call load environment, it loaded those
environment variables into memory. And then when you have this add traceable, it will add traces to our project. So
let's look at our Langsmith project online and see what's going on. So here uh if you refresh
you will find this project Langraph Learning. It wasn't there before. And when you click on it you will see the
calls. Okay. So click on it. I want to buy 20 stocks and you can see the call breakdown. Now interesting thing here is
it will show you the cost. So apparently the Google Gemini API that I'm using it's cost it's costing some money to me
284 tokens. Um you can look at the tool calls. Tool calls were of course free latency was zero. In this case latency
was 82 seconds. So see you can monitor cost you can monitor latency. You can also audit some of these calls to check
for the correct output. Okay. So whenever you are building enterprise scale application having this kind of
monitoring tool will be extremely useful and tracing is just one dimension of uh lang. It provides many other features as
well such as evaluating agents performance uh it and collaborate on prompts
monitoring you know route decisions and things like that like since this is a lang craft tutorial and not langid
tutorial I don't I don't want to go into details of those additional features but at least by doing this you set up a
basic lang project and you have your traces being collected on this dashboard let's go over another important topic
called human in the loop also known as hitl when you're building agentic workflows they can't be fully autonomous
before performing some critical action you want to take some human approval let's say you're buying stocks using
some AI system before it executes a specific trade you want to make sure everything is perfect and give a human
approval so that's what we are going to build right now to demonstrate human in the loop
I have created this Python file. I'm not using notebook to make things easier. Just a simple Python file which has get
stock price tool. We have written this code before. So it shouldn't be a surprise. When you run it, you ask the
price of 10 MS50 stocks and it will tell you. Now let's add another tool to buy the stocks. Okay? So we will say tool
and uh buy stocks. Okay. So here let's say I will also add
total price for this you know and you're just writing a dummy Python function. I I I don't want to go ahead and connect
it with my Robin Hood account and execute the trade for real. Okay. a learning tutorial but in real life you
will have some API integration you are calling whatever your stock brokerage accounts API to execute it okay so you
bought this quantity share for a total price of this very simple and then add that to this particular tools array and
then tools will go to llm with tools okay so now let's execute that Okay. So here I am going to add a second step
saying that buy 10 MSFT stocks at current price. And here
okay. So let me just run it and this is okay. Right. So it is saying I have bought 10
shares of MSFT for a total price of this. So it worked as expected folks. Sometimes I have seen that just Gemini
model behaves unpredictable way. So you might get like random output. If you want the best output you should use GPT
model. I mean of course for that you will need open AI API. Um but just be aware that sometimes you might get weird
output and it's just LLM, right? It's just unpredictable at times. Now I want to add the human in the loop component
for which we will use this interrupt function. So if you look at their documentation they have this interrupt
function which is similar to input function in Python. Whenever you want to take input from Python right like let's
say okay should I execute this trade? Yes and no. We use input function right? Interrupt is a similar function. So if
you look at the documentation you know this is how you interrupt. So let me copy paste this to import that
first obviously and then I will not buy the stocks directly. I will just say interrupt and I will say approve buying
this much right this stocks and that will be your decision and if decision is equal to yes then do this
otherwise buying decline. Okay. Now whenever it is executing and when it comes to this node when it encounters
this line it will stop execution and it will ask for human input. So how do you know it has stopped the execution? Well
here in this code uh you can just print I'll just copy paste here. So you can just print here
state.get interrupt. Okay. So when you do this see it will print this value which means the graph execution has
interrupted right. So if you look at our particular graph uh the graph nodes if you think about it right we have start
node then we have get stock prices tool right so we have a chatbot actually so this is chatbot and then it has access
to the tools so you have seen the dotted line right so tools and in tools both the tools get prize as well as execute
and there is this and then there is and correct. So now what happens is when you're buying a stock see it will come
through this nodes right? So it's in a chatboard it will make a tool call. So it will call buy tools and then it will
stop here. It will not go further ahead. It will just stop. And here is where human in the loop right? So human in the
loop will come in play where you will give some kind of output and then it will uh finish the remaining execution.
It's very straightforward folks. So I hope you're getting it. So to get that here using Python input
function I will say okay um do you want to approve like approve yes no
you want to approve that and once you have the decision you will say graph dot invoke
command. See, so you are passing decision through command. So what command will do is
whatever is decision, right? Either yes or no, it will put it here as an output of the interrupt. So when you call
interrupt, it will be blocked. And when you say command decision,
it will actually this this is the name of the argument. So in
command you're saying resume wherever you're blocked resume with this particular decision which is yes. So let
me just run it so you get an idea. Um so here it should ask yes. See approve buying this. Now you
will say yes no. So you will say yes and when you say yes it will okay let me see. So when I said yes
actually it worked. I should have printed actually here. Uh let me just print this thing. I forgot to print that
state actually that's why. Okay. So approve. Yes. And it will say um all right. Let me just debug it to
see what's going on. So I'll put a break point here. And let's run this. I hope this
interrupt and PyCharm's debugger interrupt kind of works well in the sync. Okay, approve. You will say yes.
You see decision you got it as yes. So it is a working as expected. So when you do this, it should return that that.
Okay, an obvious mistake that I was making was I need to get this back in state. Okay, so that was a problem. So I
was not returning that state back into this variable. So now when you say approve yes it should say you bought 10
stocks and if you say approval no let me try that no see I was not able to buy stocks buying
decline so it this one will return buying decline but then llm will enhance the output and it will add that the line
might look something different so I hope you got a some idea on you know how you can involve all humans in the agent AI
workflows using the interrupt and command. That's it folks. The link for the code is given in
the video description. If you have any question, post in the comment box below. Feel free to share this with your
friends who want to learn agentic AI using Langraph. And if you like this video, give it a thumbs up. Thank you
very much for watching.